<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Barlowe Analytics</title>
    <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Barlowe Analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2019 Barlowe Analytics</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 22:16:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Basics</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/sqlbasics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 22:16:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/sqlbasics/</guid>
      <description>Ok if you&amp;rsquo;ve read the first tutorial on installing Postgres and getting your first database up and running, you&amp;rsquo;re now wondering &amp;ldquo;So how do I access all this data?&amp;rdquo; Well that&amp;rsquo;s where this tutorial comes in as we are going to cover some of the basic commands in SQL to get the data we want. Ok let&amp;rsquo;s get started and dive right in to our data.
SELECT The SELECT command is going to be your workhorse command when working with SQL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Travis CI and Codecov with your Python Project</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/travis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:22:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/travis/</guid>
      <description>by Matthew Barlowe I&amp;rsquo;m going to cover two important concepts when it comes to coding: Continuous Integration and Code Coverage. Continuous Integration is the act of merging everyones code into the main code repository several times a day instead of doing it once a day or every few days.
There are pros and cons to this behavior which is beyond the scope of the article, but I like Continuous Integration (CI) because it fits in with my own coding philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re Back!</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 21:36:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>The Rebuild Has Begun Due to a lot (well a few) people asking me about my tutorials I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to bring them back. And It gives me a chance to revamp the old website with a little slicker format. So stay tuned as I slowly work to get things back in the shape they were before. As always you can address any concerns, questions, or requests to matt@barloweanaltyics.com.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>