<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Barlowe Analytics</title>
    <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Barlowe Analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2019 Barlowe Analytics</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 13:10:58 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pick A Language</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/starting_analysis/pick_a_language/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 13:10:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/starting_analysis/pick_a_language/</guid>
      <description>Pick a Language Why do this? Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing data sciencey things I often get asked for advice. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start jotting down my thoughts/opinions on a more regular basis now for several reasons.
 To have an easy place to look for when I inevitably forget whatever I&amp;rsquo;ve done in the past. To allow others to freely have access to whatever experience I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated and hopefully give them a head start.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;pick-a-language&#34;&gt;Pick a Language&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-this&#34;&gt;Why do this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing data sciencey things I often get asked for advice. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start jotting
down my thoughts/opinions on a more regular basis now for several reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To have an easy place to look for when I inevitably forget whatever I&amp;rsquo;ve done in the past.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To allow others to freely have access to whatever experience I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated and hopefully give them a head
start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like to write and writing is a valuable skill to maintain for anyone. Especially for those trying to share
their findings discovered in data to non data folks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that taken care of, let&amp;rsquo;s move on to the matter at hand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-to-start&#34;&gt;Where to start?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a common question asked by people starting to do, for lack of a better
term, what others call &amp;ldquo;analytics&amp;rdquo;. The answer I give is learn a programming language. Can
you do analytics without learning how to program? Sure, plenty do excellent work using Business
Intelligence platforms like Tableau or Power BI. There&amp;rsquo;s also the workhorse of offices across
the world: Microsoft Excel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their ease of use (and their non trivially priced licenses), will eventually limit any user wanting
to do anything outside the box. They also are severely hampered when it comes to handling datasets that are
fairly large. Both of these problems are solved with an Open Source programming language. The first because
these programming languages are free, and the second because the lack of a graphical interface like Excel allows
one to work with datasets magnitudes of orders larger than what you can fit in a single Excel Workbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;which-language&#34;&gt;Which Language?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter really, just pick one and get started. Sure there are languages that are more tailored
to analytics (and used more in the analytics&#39; communities themselves), but really ANY language will do some are just
easier to get started than others. Those languages are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-project.org&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;
(and to a lesser extent &lt;a href=&#34;https://julialang.org&#34;&gt;Julia&lt;/a&gt;). But those aren&amp;rsquo;t the only ones, there are data science packages
in almost every major programming language, even &lt;a href=&#34;https://danfo.jsdata.org&#34;&gt;JavaScript!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more one strays from R and Python, the harder it will be to do things, but it will not be impossible.
My language of choice is Python, and I think its better than the others. Those reasons have nothing to do with
the other language&amp;rsquo;s lack of capabilities at getting the job done, and anyone that tries to say otherwise can
most likely be ignored. Not sure which one to pick? Flip a coin and off you go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are moving from Excel, this process will be hard and slow. Things you are used to doing in minutes can
take hours if you are just starting out. But give it time, eventually you will learn to do things in minutes that
would take you hours in Excel!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;once-youve-started&#34;&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning a programming language is not an overnight process unfortunately. The process is often
similar to learning a spoken language; nothing can replace the experience of using one. It will take, and
I can&amp;rsquo;t stress this enough, time. That&amp;rsquo;s it. No fancy math is necessary. Just the ability to invest time
on a regular basis to learning the language itself. The payoff though will be well worth the investment.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gamma Distribution</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/math/stats/gamma_distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 02:03:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/math/stats/gamma_distribution/</guid>
      <description>The Gamma Distribution The Gamma Distribution is a very useful distribution used to model Poisson processes. The Poisson distribution determines the probability of a number of events in a given time span. The Gamma distribution gives the probability of a given wait time until the \(n\)th event is observed in that process.
Gamma Distribution Parameters The Gamma Distribution can be defined by two different sets of two parameters. It can have a shape parameter of \({k}\) and a scale parameter of \(\theta\) (theta) or a shape parameter of \(\alpha\) (alpha) and a rate parameter of \(\beta\) (beta).</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-gamma-distribution&#34;&gt;The Gamma Distribution&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gamma Distribution is a very useful distribution used to model Poisson processes.
The Poisson distribution determines the probability of a number of
events in a given time span. The Gamma distribution gives the probability
of a given wait time until the &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(n\)&lt;/span&gt;th event is observed in that process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;gamma-distribution-parameters&#34;&gt;Gamma Distribution Parameters&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gamma Distribution can be defined by two different sets of two parameters.
It can have a shape parameter of &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\({k}\)&lt;/span&gt; and a scale parameter of &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\theta\)&lt;/span&gt; (theta) or a
shape parameter of &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\alpha\)&lt;/span&gt; (alpha) and a rate parameter of &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\beta\)&lt;/span&gt; (beta).
With either set of parameters &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\alpha={k}\)&lt;/span&gt; and  &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\beta={1/\theta}\)&lt;/span&gt;.
&lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\beta\)&lt;/span&gt; is also equal to the &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\lambda\)&lt;/span&gt; of the Poisson process we are trying
to model with the Gamma Distribution.
Gamma distribution parameters can only be positive real numbers, meaning you can
never have a parameter for a gamma distribution be negative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;moments-of-the-gamma-distribution&#34;&gt;Moments of the Gamma Distribution&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mean or expected value of a Gamma distribution is defined like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\[\mathop{{}\mathbb{E}}{[X]} = {k}\theta = \frac{\alpha}{\beta}\]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\mathop{{}\mathbb{E}}{[X]}\)&lt;/span&gt; is the symbolic way of saying the &amp;quot;Expected Value of X&amp;quot;.
Meaning that on average if you randomly drew a number from this distribution with these
parameters the average value of the draws would equal this number.  If you have worked
with the Normal/Gaussian distribution you have seen this expressed as &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\mu\)&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The variance is defined thusly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\[\mathop{{}\mathbb{V}}{[X]} = {k}\theta^{2} = \frac{\alpha}{\beta^{2}}\]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\mathop{{}\mathbb{V}}{[X]}\)&lt;/span&gt; can also be displayed as &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\textnormal{Var}({X})\)&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\sigma^{2}\)&lt;/span&gt; when
dealing with Normal/Gaussian distributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;purposes-of-the-gamma-distribution&#34;&gt;Purposes of the Gamma Distribution&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gamma Distribution is used to predict the wait time until a future event happens. More specifically until
the &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\({k}\)&lt;/span&gt;th event happens of a Poisson random variable. So if we wanted to model the time it takes
until the fifth time some event happens in a Poisson process the Gamma Distribution would be
our go-to distribution.  The Gamma Function models the wait time between Poisson distributed events.
Or another way to put it is the Gamma models the time spent in each state between events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Aerin Kim notes in her excellent piece on the Gamma Distribution (link below in the sources):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poisson, Exponential, and Gamma distribution model different aspects of the same process.
Poisson distribution is used to model the # of events in the future, Exponential distribution
is used to predict the wait time &lt;strong&gt;until the very first event&lt;/strong&gt;, and Gamma distribution is
used to predict the wait time &lt;strong&gt;until the &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\({k}\)&lt;/span&gt;th event&lt;/strong&gt;. (Kim)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So basically let&#39;s say that a catastrophic flood happens in your area once in a hundred years.
This would be our rate of occurrences, or &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\lambda\)&lt;/span&gt;, of the Poisson process. So if we wanted
to know how long we would have to wait to see five catastrophic floods we would use a Gamma
distribution with the parameters of &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\alpha = 5\)&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\theta = 1/\lambda\)&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\theta\)&lt;/span&gt; is our average wait time between events in our unit of time or rate parameter, which in this case is
100 years. Since one divided by one is one that means our average wait time between floods
that occur once every 100 years is one unit of our time interval which in this case is 100 years.
If our rate of floods was 5 every 100 years then &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\theta\)&lt;/span&gt; would be .20 or 20 years on average
between floods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\alpha\)&lt;/span&gt; is our number of times we want the event to occur in this case 5
because we want to calculate the probability of wait times before the area experiences 5
catastrophic floods. Using the formulas above the expected value of our wait time
would be 500 years (&lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\alpha * \theta\)&lt;/span&gt;) with a variance of 500 years squared as well &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(5\cdot1^{2}\)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if we want to calculate the probability of the wait time for 5 catastrophic floods being
100 years or less? To calculate this we would just plug our parameters into the Gamma CDF
(In this case the exact function is the Erlang CDF because the math is easier, but the Erlang is just
a special case of the Gamma where &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\alpha\)&lt;/span&gt; is a positive integer) function. Here both &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\lambda\)&lt;/span&gt;
and &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\({t}\)&lt;/span&gt; are equal to one since our rate (&lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\lambda\)&lt;/span&gt;) is one and our interval of wait time (&lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\({t}\)&lt;/span&gt;) is one.
Don&#39;t confuse this with the &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\lambda\)&lt;/span&gt; of the Poisson process that is actually
&lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\lambda={rate}\cdot{t}\)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\[\begin{aligned} {P(T\le1)}&amp;={CDF(1)} \\ &amp;={1 - P(\text{events}\lt5 \text{ in interval t})} \\ &amp;=1 - \sum_{n=0}^{\alpha-1}\frac{(\lambda{t})^{n}\exp^{-\lambda{t}}}{{n}!} \\ &amp;=1 - \sum_{n=0}^{4}\frac{(1)^{n}\exp^{-1}}{{n}!} \end{aligned}\]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing the math on that will give us the value of .003 or .3% probability of seeing 5 catastrophic floods
in the interval of 100 years. If we wanted the probability of 5 floods in say 300 years or less our formula would look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\[1 - \sum_{n=0}^{4}\frac{(3)^{n}\exp^{-1}}{{n}!}\]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which gives us a probability of roughly .18. But enough of doing this by hand lets see how to do it in
python. I&#39;m going to use the &lt;code&gt;scipy&lt;/code&gt; package which contains all sorts of probability distributions including
the gamma. The CDF function takes parameters of the wait time or interval, &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\alpha\)&lt;/span&gt;, and scale which is equal to
our &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(\theta\)&lt;/span&gt; parameter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;from scipy.stats import gamma

#probability we see 5 floods in one interval of time or less
#with scale parameter equal to 1
gamma.cdf(1, 5, scale=1)
0.003659846827343713

#probability we see 5 floods in three intervals of time or less
#with scale parameter equal to 1
gamma.cdf(3, 5, scale=1)
0.18473675547622787

#probability we see 1 flood in three intervals of time or less
#with scale parameter equal to 1
gamma.cdf(3, 1, scale=1)
0.950212931632136&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to dive deeper into using the gamma function to model wait times for Poisson processes
please read the links below as they go into much great detail on the gamma function and its uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/gamma-distribution-intuition-derivation-and-examples-55f407423840&#34;&gt;Gamma Distribution -- Intuition, Derivation, and Examples&lt;/a&gt; by Aerin Kim&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mygreatlearning.com/blog/gamma-distribution/&#34;&gt;Gamma Distribution Explained | What is Gamma Distribution&lt;/a&gt; by Somak Sengupta&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.stat.ucla.edu/socr/index.php/AP_Statistics_Curriculum_2007_Gamma&#34;&gt;UCLA AP Statistics Curriculum 2007 Gamma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sherrytowers.com/2016/01/23/poisson-and-exponential-distributions/&#34;&gt;Poisson, Exponential, and Gamma distributions&lt;/a&gt; by Sherry Towers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/seven-must-know-statistical-distributions-and-their-simulations-for-data-science-681c5ac41e32&#34;&gt;Seven Must-Know Statistical Distributions and Their Simulations for Data Science&lt;/a&gt; by Zijing Zhu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/geekculture/how-to-model-time-between-events-using-the-exponential-gamma-and-poisson-distributions-4b058a357a55&#34;&gt;How to Model Time Between Events Using the Exponential, Gamma, and Poisson Distributions&lt;/a&gt; by Federico Riveroll&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://online.stat.psu.edu/stat414/lesson/introduction-stat-414&#34;&gt;Introduction to STAT 414&lt;/a&gt; Penn State Department of Statistics&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDEs of March</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/ides-of-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 01:39:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/ides-of-march/</guid>
      <description>IDEs of March There are many articles about learning to code and mention where to learn or how to learn etc. Very few however mention where you are going to write the code once you learn it! Most beginner stuff have you working at that programming language&amp;rsquo;s terminal, which is great for getting the basics but you&amp;rsquo;ll quickly grow past that. So where does one actually write their source code? A lot of people use what&amp;rsquo;s called an IDE which stands for Integrated Development Envrionment.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ides-of-march&#34;&gt;IDEs of March&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many articles about learning to code and mention where to learn
or how to learn etc. Very few however mention where you are going to write
the code once you learn it! Most beginner stuff have you working at that programming
language&amp;rsquo;s terminal, which is great for getting the basics but you&amp;rsquo;ll quickly grow past
that. So where does one actually write their source code? A lot of people use what&amp;rsquo;s
called an IDE which stands for Integrated Development Envrionment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;whats-the-story-morning-glory&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the Story Morning Glory&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Codeacademy gives a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codecademy.com/articles/what-is-an-ide&#34;&gt;breif rundown&lt;/a&gt; and they
generally have these features: text editor, syntax highlighting, autocomplete, compiler(if needed),
and a debugger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A text editor is the most important part. If you are completely new to coding, you are probably used
to writing things in some sort of program like Word or Apple Docs. These programs are completely useless
it comes to storing code because they have tons of metadata in the text that you don&amp;rsquo;t see that
determines things like font size or type or margins etc. When you try to run this through a compiler
or an interpreter the program won&amp;rsquo;t know what to do with them and will create an error that prevents
the script from running. A text editor in its most basic form is the basic notepad program for both Mac and Windows. IDE&amp;rsquo;s just
take these editors and add a bunch of bells and whistles to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syntax highlighting is a benefit where certain key words are highlighted so you can quickly parse the code.
These are usually syntax to create functions or classes. Comments often have a different color than executable
code. There are a lot of different color schemes for syntax highlighting. My favorite is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pR0Ps/molokai-dark&#34;&gt;Molokai Dark&lt;/a&gt;
and while it is a vim color scheme I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure its been ported to the IDEs will talk about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autocomplete is more of argued about benefit of IDEs. Some people love it and some hate it. If you&amp;rsquo;re just starting
out I would lean more towards using it because its good at helping you remember function/variable names in packages.
Some people hate it because it can get in the way when you are trying to code and autocomplete the wrong things if
they have similar names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you&amp;rsquo;re writing a compiled langauge(C++, Java) then the built in compiler is not a huge issue. But even for
things like Python/R there will be built in terminals where you can run your code with leaving the IDE environment
which will be key to not breaking your concentration. Lastly there are debuggers, I personally don&amp;rsquo;t use them because
I&amp;rsquo;m dumb but some people swear by them so being able to set break points for your code and stuff is really useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now don&amp;rsquo;t expect to download these and immediately get started coding as they do take some setup. For the most
part though its minimal to be able to start writing code to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-what-are-my-choices&#34;&gt;So What are My Choices&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are quite a few choices out there some free, some not. This won&amp;rsquo;t be an exhaustive list but there will be
enough choice to cover most of the people&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;visual-studio-code&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt; is what I recommend for just about everyone. It&amp;rsquo;s free and open
source. Its backed by Microsoft so it won&amp;rsquo;t stopped being maintained for now reason. And it has tons of plugins you can
download that will allow you to work with any language. It has full Git integration and a built in terminal as well allowing
you to run code without leaving the environment. It works on Windows/Mac/Linux as well so you can use it on any platform.
Visual Studio Code also has tons of customization so you can configure it to do almost anything you want once you get to that
point. If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this to get &amp;ldquo;the best&amp;rdquo; IDE (no such things exists though!) then this would be my choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rstudio&#34;&gt;Rstudio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only time I disagree with what I said above is if you are going to be working in R then you need to use
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.com/products/rstudio/&#34;&gt;Rstudio&lt;/a&gt;. Its not quite as customizable as VS Code in terms of packages
being developed by others, but it is probably the best IDE when work with code in a pure data evironment. It also
integrates with Git and has built in terminals and command line so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to leave as well. Rstudio also
allows you to build &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;Rmarkdown files&lt;/a&gt; which is one of the easiest ways you can share
your findings as you can directly host them on &lt;a href=&#34;https://rpubs.com/&#34;&gt;Rpubs&lt;/a&gt; for free. If you work in R this is the easiest
way to build a portfolio to show to perspective employers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;atom&#34;&gt;Atom&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://atom.io/&#34;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt; is another IDE developed by GitHub. It seems to be more tuned to frontend developers esepcially
those working in Javascript, but I have set it up to use Python and I&amp;rsquo;m sure it can be configured for almost every language.
It is also customizable by downloading user made packages like VS code. Technically Atom isn&amp;rsquo;t a true IDE anymore but rather
a souped up text editor. But there are ways to add on those functionalities. Me personally I found Atom to be bloated and
clunky and it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be my first choice. But some people like it so I thought I would include it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;others&#34;&gt;Others&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;python-spyder&#34;&gt;Python Spyder&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spyder-ide.org/&#34;&gt;Spyder&lt;/a&gt; is python&amp;rsquo;s answer to Rstudio and like pandas to tidyverse it does enough but still feels
clunky. I haven&amp;rsquo;t used it in a while so take what I say with a grain of salt but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t my favorite. However if you want something
close to Rstudio, but don&amp;rsquo;t want to work in R (completely understandable), this is the best best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;jetbrains&#34;&gt;Jetbrains&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/&#34;&gt;Jetbrains&lt;/a&gt; makes a lot of good IDEs that are tailored to their individual langauge such as Pycharm for
python, IntelliJ for Java, and Datagrips for SQL. These are not free but I have used them and there are some key benefits to paying.
One is you don&amp;rsquo;t have to rely on user created packages to add functionality and two you get actual support instead of having to scour
the internet to fix things. Again I feel VScode is just as good as these with a little extra work but if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to put the time
in and have the money consider paying for a license for these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;only-read-past-here-if-you-are-truly-a-masochist&#34;&gt;Only Read Past Here if You Are Truly a Masochist&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for the record I don&amp;rsquo;t use any of these options for anything I do. Not. Use. A. Single. One. I actually craft my own IDE by combining a
bunch of different packages built around using &lt;a href=&#34;https://neovim.io/&#34;&gt;Neovim&lt;/a&gt; as my text editor. Neovim is an upgraded version of Vim which
was an improvment on Vi released in 1991. This is a text editor that has no mouse and you navigate around your code using entirely your
keyboard. It is not for the faint of heart and has a steep learning curve but if you have time to learn it you will be well rewarded
because Vim is a ubiqutous text editor that comes with all linux/unix systems and you&amp;rsquo;ll never not be able to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to neovim I install several packages to help me work. The first is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/preservim/nerdtree&#34;&gt;NerdTree&lt;/a&gt; for navigating
directories of files. The next is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vim-airline/vim-airline&#34;&gt;Airline&lt;/a&gt; to improve my status bar. After that is
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vim-syntastic/syntastic&#34;&gt;Syntastic&lt;/a&gt; to handle all the linting for the languages I&amp;rsquo;m writing in. And lastly
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ervandew/supertab&#34;&gt;Supertab&lt;/a&gt; to handle my autocompletion. I&amp;rsquo;ve also used &lt;a href=&#34;https://kite.com/&#34;&gt;Kite&lt;/a&gt; for python things
which I really like as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this is dificult to setup and maintain so don&amp;rsquo;t choose this until you feel you are ready. Honestly you may find you never want this
as Vim keystrokes can be added to almost any IDE these days. However if you find you want true customization of your text editor and IDE then
this is the only way to go. It is not for the faint of heart though and learning it is hard. However, if you decide to embark down this
path of darkness feel free to reach out to me and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to help you as much as I can.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want to Learn to Code</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/learning_to_code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 22:52:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/learning_to_code/</guid>
      <description>So You Want to Learn to Code I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting a lot of inquiries recently asking a lot of similar quesitions. Often these questions are broad and hard to answer in an email or a DM, so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to use my free time no longer taken up by watching sports to write a series of blog posts to answer them as best I can.
One of the big ones I keep seeing over and over again is &amp;ldquo;What are the best resources to learn to code?</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-you-want-to-learn-to-code&#34;&gt;So You Want to Learn to Code&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting a lot of inquiries recently asking a lot of similar quesitions.
Often these questions are broad and hard to answer in an email or a DM, so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided
to use my free time no longer taken up by watching sports to write a series of blog
posts to answer them as best I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the big ones I keep seeing over and over again is &amp;ldquo;What are the best resources to
learn to code?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;How can I get started coding?&amp;rdquo; Questions like these are very hard to answer
because everyone learns differently and what some find easy others may find dificult. This post
will focuse on resources &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve&lt;/strong&gt; found helpful in teaching myself to code. Will they work for you?
Maybe, or maybe not but a lot of these are used/recommended by others so I&amp;rsquo;m hoping they
work for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the first step is to pick a programming language to learn. Which language should you pick?
It really doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, the key is to stick with it long enough to learn it well because once
you do the same ideas will carry over from language to language. Most people asking me are wanting
to learn a programming language in order to do some type of &amp;ldquo;analytics&amp;rdquo;. This post will generally
tackle things from that view point, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to include some frontend resources
(skills also very important in analytics though for different reasons) in case someone
is interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two of the most popular langauges in analytics is R and python. Which one should you choose?
Again it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, just pick one and learn it! This part is going to take some time.
You&amp;rsquo;ll be doing a lot of boring stuff just to learn the basics of the language before you can
start working on the cool stuf. But don&amp;rsquo;t get discouraged and &lt;strong&gt;stick with it!&lt;/strong&gt; The key to learning
things isn&amp;rsquo;t smarts, but rather time, so keep chipping away at it every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer here Python is my language of choice. It&amp;rsquo;s what I use for everything I do so I&amp;rsquo;m a bit biased
in favor of it. However, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t it make it perfect by any means so if you decide its not for you don&amp;rsquo;t
feel bad. In fact I started learning R, didn&amp;rsquo;t like it, and then switched to Python. So if you&amp;rsquo;re just starting
and you don&amp;rsquo;t like it then don&amp;rsquo;t fall for a sunk cost fallacy. Switch things up and see if other languages
are easier to grasp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One link I&amp;rsquo;ll start out with is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codecademy.com/&#34;&gt;Code Academy&lt;/a&gt;. It has a bunch of intro
lessons for all sorts of languages. And its a site that if I need to learn a new language and they have
a lesson on it I always go through that lesson. There is premium content but most of it is free and
its enough to get you started with any language you want to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;beginner-python-resources&#34;&gt;Beginner Python Resources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite beginner python books is &lt;a href=&#34;https://automatetheboringstuff.com/&#34;&gt;Automate the Boring Stuff&lt;/a&gt;
by Al Sweigart. Not only is it good for beginners, the problems it uses to teach you programming are problems
you&amp;rsquo;ll need to solve as a programmer. Things like file manipulation, web scraping, and working with
spreadsheets in python are all skills you will need in analytics and this book does a great job of
breaking things down. If you make it through the entire book you&amp;rsquo;ll come out the other side with
enough skills in python to do whatever you want next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next I recommend if you don&amp;rsquo;t like reading is a class on EdX taught by MIT called
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edx.org/course/introduction-to-computer-science-and-programming-7&#34;&gt;Intro to Computer Science and Programming using Python&lt;/a&gt;.
It is a more broad course that focuses on important Computer Science ideas like loops,
recursion, functions, and objects. These are all very important ideas to learn and know when
learning programming as the translate to almost EVERY programming language and are a shared
vocabulary. Even if I program in Java and you program in Python, I can say I did this by
writing a for loop you&amp;rsquo;ll know what I mean and could replicate it in your own language as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;beginner-r-resources&#34;&gt;Beginner R Resources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not as familiar with R but I have learned it and can work in it, but others may have better
resources than me. If you know something better for beginners then let me know &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:matt@barloweanaltyics.com&#34;&gt;matt@barloweanaltyics.com&lt;/a&gt;
and I&amp;rsquo;ll add it to the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course I used to mainly use R was this one from Udacity I took while working on my Data Analyst
Nanodegree from them. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.udacity.com/course/data-analysis-with-r--ud651&#34;&gt;Data Analysis with R&lt;/a&gt; is
a free course you can go through all the lessons. I highly recommend it, and anything else from Udacity as well
researched that will give you a good coverage of the basics to build on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next package I used is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://swirlstats.com/&#34;&gt;Swirl Package&lt;/a&gt;. This is an interactive package that
will allow you to learn R while running R. So its similar to the Code Academy courses I posted above just
not on a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly I found this site while researching this post. Disclaimer I haven&amp;rsquo;t worked through it but it seems free
and the first three lessons I skimmed through are very informative. If you go through it and had a bad experience
let me know and I&amp;rsquo;ll change my review on it. This site &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.guru99.com/r-tutorial.html&#34;&gt;R Tutorial for Beginners&lt;/a&gt;
even goes over the install process for R as well which could be very handy as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;other-resources&#34;&gt;Other Resources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other site I worked on when I was first starting out was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freecodecamp.org/&#34;&gt;Free Code Camp&lt;/a&gt;.
Its focus is mainly frontend design using javascript, but that still contains a lot of good knowledge that
has come in handy a lot of times for me. They also have a good &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;
that posts articles about learning to code, tutorials, and about coding in general. All of it is well done
and they have a great community focused on learning and beginnings. Even if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to do Javascript
some of their stuff on coding philosophies is worth the time to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example here&amp;rsquo;s an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/a-gentler-introduction-to-programming-1f57383a1b2c/&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;
that goes in depth on the broad concepts of what programming is that you
might find interesting if you are first starting out.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability and Statistics: Chapter 1</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/degrootchapter1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 15:34:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/degrootchapter1/</guid>
      <description>Ok this is going to be a series of blog posts about detaling my notes and thoughts as I work through DeGroot and Schervish&amp;rsquo;s Probability and Statistics 4th Edition. This may be useful to you it may not be but I generally find I learn things better if I write down what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about them so without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s begin!
The History of Probability So apparently people have been gambling forever.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Ok this is going to be a series of blog posts about detaling my notes and thoughts as
I work through DeGroot and &lt;em&gt;Schervish&amp;rsquo;s Probability and Statistics 4th Edition.&lt;/em&gt; This may be
useful to you it may not be but I generally find I learn things better if I write down
what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about them so without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s begin!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-history-of-probability&#34;&gt;The History of Probability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So apparently people have been gambling forever. Balise Pascal and Pierre Fermat started the
mathematical theory of probability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;interpretations-of-probability&#34;&gt;Interpretations of Probability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently nobody can agree on a single scientific interpretation of what the term &lt;em&gt;probability&lt;/em&gt; means. I wonder what the probability of that happening is? But there seems to
be three main different interpretations of probablity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequency Interpretaion of Probability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the probability of a specific outcome of a process will be obtained is interpreted as
the relative frequency that outcome is obtained if the process were repeated a large number
of times under similar conditions. However there are some problems with this definition.
The main thing being that the ideas are rather vague. &amp;ldquo;Large number&amp;rdquo; has no defnitive
measurement of what the number should be to be considered large enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, its stating that the experiment should be repeated under similar conditions but
again the conditions are not precisely described. The situations can&amp;rsquo;t be exactly identical
or else the results would always be the same. So the trials have to have some random features in them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thirdly a shortcoming of the frequency interpretation of probability is that it applies only to
a problem where there are a large number of similar repetitions of a similar problem. Some
examples are that frequency interpretation can&amp;rsquo;t be used to determine the probability that a
friend will get married or that a research project will lead to the development of a new
treatment for a disease in a period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classical Interpretation of Probability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The classical interpretation of probability is based on the concept of equally likely outcomes
and the sums of the probabilities must equal 1. For example with a coin there are only two possible outcomes and if we assume that both outcomes are equally likely they have the same
probability and since the probabilities must equal one then their probabilities must be 1/2. To
generalize if the outcome of some process is one of &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; different outcomes and if those outcomes
are equally likely to occur then the probability of each outcome is 1/&lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main flaws when attempting to define a formal definition of probability from this
interpretation. One the concept of equally likely outcomes is based on the concept of probability
we are try to define. Two possible outcomes that are equally likely is the same as two outcomes have the same probability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second no systematic method is given for assigning probabilities to outcomes were we don&amp;rsquo;t assume
them all to be equally likely. Look back at the problem of determing the probability of a friend
getting married. No reasonable person would assume all outcomes of that situation to be equally likely so a different method would be needed to determine the probabilities of each outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subjective Interpretation of Probability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subjective interpretation of probability is that the probability a person assigns to a
possible outcome of some process represents their own judgment of the likelihood that the
outcome will be obtained. If people&amp;rsquo;s judgements of the relative likelihoods of various combinations of outcomes satisfy certain conditions of consistency then it can be shown that
their subjective probabilities of the different possible events can be uniquely determined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The downfalls to this is that the idea that a person&amp;rsquo;s judgements be free from contradictions
or biases does not seem humanly possible unless the person is willing to adopt a collection of
judgements known to be consistent. Also these subjective interpretations provide no objective
basis for two or more  people working together to reach a common evaluation of the state of
knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the mathematical theory of probability can be done without regard to the controversies of
the different interpretations of the term probability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;experiments-and-events&#34;&gt;Experiments and Events&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An experiment is any process, real or hypothetical, in which the possible outcomes can be
identified ahead of time. An event is a well defined set of possible outcomes of the experiment.
The probability of each event is the way of saying how likely it is that the outcome of the
experiment is in the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once probabilities have been assigned to outcomes there is agreementthat the mathematical
theory of probability provides the appropriate methodology to further study probabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;set-theory&#34;&gt;Set Theory&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sample Space:&lt;/strong&gt; The collection of all possible outcomes of an experiment is called the sample
space of the experiment. This space can also be thought of as a set or colleciton of the
different possible outcomes. Each outcome is a &lt;em&gt;point&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;element&lt;/em&gt; in the sample space and
events are &lt;em&gt;subsets&lt;/em&gt; of the sample space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example with rolling a six sided dice the sample space is the six numbers on the dice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S = {1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One event we call &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; is an even number is rolled on the dice represented thusly &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; = {2, 4, 6}.
Another event is rolling a number greater than 2 then the subset of our sample space would
be &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt; = {3, 4, 5, 6}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The collections of sets called events will have three conditions for the rest of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Condition 1: The sample space &lt;em&gt;S&lt;/em&gt; must be an event where &lt;em&gt;S&lt;/em&gt; is the sample space of some
experiment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Containment:&lt;/strong&gt; it is said that a set &lt;em&gt;A is contained in&lt;/em&gt; another set &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt; if every element of
the set &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; also belongs to the set &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;. This is expressed by A ⊂ B which says A is a subset
of B. Also can say that B contains A and also write B ⊃ A. For events this means that if A
occurs then so does B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theorem 1.4.1:&lt;/strong&gt; Let A, B, and C be events. then A ⊂ S. If A ⊂ B and B ⊂ A, then A=B. If A⊂B and B ⊂ C, then A ⊂ C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theorem 1.4.3:&lt;/strong&gt; Let A be an event then ∅ ⊂ A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Countable/Uncountable:&lt;/strong&gt; An infinite set A is countable if there is a one to one
correspondence between the elements of A and the set of natural numbers {1, 2, 3, &amp;hellip;}. A set is uncountable if it is neither finite nor countable. If it is said
that a set has at most countably many elements then the set is either finite or countable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of countably infinite sets include the integers, even integers, odd integers,
the prime numbers, and any infinite sequence. these sets can be put in one to one
correspondence with the natural numbers. Every infinite sequence of distinct items
is a countable set as its indexing puts it in one to one correspondence with the natural numbers. Examples of uncountable sets are the real numbers, the positive
reals, numbers in the interval [0, 1], and the set of all ordered pairs of real
numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;operation-of-set-theory&#34;&gt;Operation of Set Theory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complement:&lt;/strong&gt; The complement of a set A is defined to be the set that contains all
elements of the sample space S that do not belong to A. In terms of events the
compliment event of A is the event that A does not occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Condition 2:&lt;/strong&gt; If A is an event then the compliment of A is also an event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If A is an event the the compliment of the compliment of A is A. The compleiment of the empty set is S the sample space and the compilment of the sample space is the empty set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Union of Two Sets:&lt;/strong&gt; If A and B are any two sets, the union of A and B is defined
to be the set containing all outcomes that belong to A alon, to B alone, or to both
A and B. The notation for the union of A and B is A ∪ B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all sets A and B,
A ∪ B = B ∪ A,
A ∪ A = A,
A ∪ Ac = S,
A ∪ ∅ = A,
A ∪ S = S.
Furthermore, if A ⊂ B, then A ∪ B = B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Union of Many Sets:&lt;/strong&gt; the union of n sets A₁, &amp;hellip;, An is defined to be the set that
contains all outcomes that bleong to at least one of these n sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of events the union of a colleciton of events is the event that at least
one of the events in the collections occurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Condition 3:&lt;/strong&gt; If A1, A2, . . . is a countable collection of events, then the union of all the events also an event.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Basics</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/sqlbasics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 22:16:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/sqlbasics/</guid>
      <description>Ok if you&amp;rsquo;ve read the first tutorial on installing Postgres and getting your first database up and running, you&amp;rsquo;re now wondering &amp;ldquo;So how do I access all this data?&amp;rdquo; Well that&amp;rsquo;s where this tutorial comes in as we are going to cover some of the basic commands in SQL to get the data we want. Ok let&amp;rsquo;s get started and dive right in to our data.
SELECT The SELECT command is going to be your workhorse command when working with SQL.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Ok if you&amp;rsquo;ve read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://barloweanalytics.com/sql/install/&#34;&gt;first tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on installing Postgres
and getting your first database up and running, you&amp;rsquo;re now wondering &amp;ldquo;So how do I access all
this data?&amp;rdquo; Well that&amp;rsquo;s where this tutorial comes in as we are going to cover some of the basic
commands in SQL to get the data we want. Ok let&amp;rsquo;s get started and dive right in to our data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SELECT&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;SELECT&lt;/code&gt; command is going to be your workhorse command when working with
SQL. It&#39;s the command that tells Postgres to pull the data from the table and return it to you
so you can use it. The &lt;code&gt;SELECT&lt;/code&gt; is always paired with a &lt;code&gt;FROM&lt;/code&gt; clause
so you can tell Postgres exactly what table you want to select your data. Let&#39;s take a look
at the command I used at the end of the first tutorial:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#39;Command Line&#39;&gt;
SELECT * FROM appearances LIMIT 10;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok let&#39;s break it down piece by piece. &lt;code&gt;SELECT&lt;/code&gt; tells Postgres that we want to
pull data. The &lt;code&gt;\*&lt;/code&gt; tells Postgres that we want the data from every column in the
table. You can choose whatever columns you want the data from and it doesn&#39;t have to be all of
them, but this example we are taking all of them. Next is the &lt;code&gt;FROM&lt;/code&gt; clause that tells
Postgres we want to pull all the columns from the &lt;code&gt;appearances&lt;/code&gt; table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have multiple tables you would change the name of the table to whatever table you wanted
data from. In order to get a list of all the tables you can select form type `\dt` and hit enter and
Postgres will list all the tables in the public schema. The &lt;code&gt;LIMIT&lt;/code&gt; clause while technically not needed
for a &lt;code&gt;SELECT&lt;/code&gt; query is very important here. If we had just entered in the command without
using the &lt;code&gt;LIMIT&lt;/code&gt; Postgres would have returned every single row in the table and you almost
never want to do that when just trying to look at the data in a table. So I added the &lt;code&gt;LIMIT&lt;/code&gt;
clause and passed it the number 1 telling Postgres to limit the results to 10 rows. Pretty simple eh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok lets do a couple other &lt;code&gt;SELECT&lt;/code&gt; queries to get the hang of it. First though
lets get a list of the columns in our table with the &lt;code&gt;\d+ appearances&lt;/code&gt; which will produce
and output similar to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;      Column   |       Type       | Collation | Nullable | Default | Storage  | Stats target | Description
    -----------+------------------+-----------+----------+---------+----------+--------------+-------------
     yearID    | bigint           |           |          |         | plain    |              |
     teamID    | text             |           |          |         | extended |              |
     lgID      | text             |           |          |         | extended |              |
     playerID  | text             |           |          |         | extended |              |
     G_all     | bigint           |           |          |         | plain    |              |
     GS        | double precision |           |          |         | plain    |              |
     G_batting | bigint           |           |          |         | plain    |              |
     G_defense | double precision |           |          |         | plain    |              |
     G_p       | bigint           |           |          |         | plain    |              |
     G_c       | bigint           |           |          |         | plain    |              |
     G_1b      | bigint           |           |          |         | plain    |              |
     G_2b      | bigint           |           |          |         | plain    |              |
     G_3b      | bigint           |           |          |         | plain    |              |
     G_ss      | bigint           |           |          |         | plain    |              |
     G_lf      | bigint           |           |          |         | plain    |              |
     G_cf      | bigint           |           |          |         | plain    |              |
     G_rf      | bigint           |           |          |         | plain    |              |
     G_of      | bigint           |           |          |         | plain    |              |
     G_dh      | double precision |           |          |         | plain    |              |
     G_ph      | double precision |           |          |         | plain    |              |
     G_pr      | double precision |           |          |         | plain    |              |
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This table in the database lists the number of appearances at each position for each player, each season
and each team. G_1b is games at first base and so on. If you need more info about the data
in the database the data dictionary can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.seanlahman.com/files/database/readme2012.txt&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now we have some columns lets adjust our &lt;code&gt;SELECT&lt;/code&gt; statement to just include a few
of them instead of all of them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side note here. When I was creating this database file for you I forgot that Postgres only stores column names
in lower case. As you can see above it does recognize upper case when displaying the column. The problem comes
when you want to select a column. If you tried to execute &lt;code&gt;SELECT playerID from appearances limit 10;&lt;/code&gt; you would
get an error saying &lt;code&gt;HINT:  Perhaps you meant to reference the column &amp;quot;appearances.playerID&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;. But even if you added
appearances to your column selection you would still get the same error. THe solution is to add &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; around each
column name so that the column is searched for on a case sensitive basis. But that&amp;rsquo;s annoying so lets fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logout of your current account with &lt;code&gt;\q&lt;/code&gt; and log back in with the superuser account that is the same
name as your computer user name and run this code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;\t on
select &#39;ALTER TABLE &#39;||&#39;&amp;quot;&#39;||table_name||&#39;&amp;quot;&#39;||&#39; RENAME COLUMN &#39;||&#39;&amp;quot;&#39;||column_name||&#39;&amp;quot;&#39;||&#39; TO &#39; || lower(column_name)||&#39;;&#39;
from information_schema.columns
where table_schema = &#39;public&#39; and lower(column_name) != column_name
\g /tmp/go_to_lower
\i /tmp/go_to_lower
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copy this and paste it into the terminal and hit enter and all your column names will be in lower case. I put this
in the tutorial for a very good reason. I could have gone back and fixed the file and changed a couple
things and made it look like I&amp;rsquo;m perfect, but I&amp;rsquo;m not. Mistakes happen. A lot. Things are going
break and a vital skill is to learn how to fix them. In this case I literally googled
&amp;lsquo;convert all columnames to lowercase postgres&amp;rsquo; and the answer was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/10086532/how-can-i-convert-all-columns-in-my-database-to-case-insensitive&#34;&gt;second link&lt;/a&gt;
on google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I know exactly what that code does? Nope but what better place to learn than in a situation
with no ramifications for it being wrong. Now knowing what to google comes with experience,
but a good place to start is to just cut and paste the error into google and start clicking.
This is what every professional programmer does and the ones that say they don&amp;rsquo;t are lying.
Ok back to the tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#39;Command Line&#39;&gt;
SELECT playerid, teamid, g\_1b, g\_2b, g\_cf FROM appearances LIMIT 10;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which will produce an output similar to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;playerid  | teamid | g_1b | g_2b | g_cf
-----------+--------+------+------+------
 abercda01 | TRO    |    0 |    0 |    0
 addybo01  | RC1    |    0 |   22 |    0
 allisar01 | CL1    |    0 |    2 |   29
 allisdo01 | WS3    |    0 |    0 |    0
 ansonca01 | RC1    |    1 |    2 |    0
 armstbo01 | FW1    |    0 |    0 |   11
 barkeal01 | RC1    |    0 |    0 |    0
 barnero01 | BS1    |    0 |   16 |    0
 barrebi01 | FW1    |    0 |    0 |    0
 barrofr01 | BS1    |    0 |    1 |    0
(10 rows)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can play around with the columns as much as you want and see the different outputs.
So now we&#39;re getting some more info that is something we can work with but nothing we can actually
draw insights from. The next clause though will help us narrow our data even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;WHERE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So above we learned how to limit the columns the SQL query returns so now lets learn how to
limit the rows that are returned. This is done in SQL by using the &lt;code&gt;WHERE&lt;/code&gt; clause
with your &lt;code&gt;SELECT&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code&gt;WHERE&lt;/code&gt; gives your an SQL query a condition that it
checks every row against in the table and if the condition is met it returns the row and if it
isn&#39;t then the row is excluded. Let&#39;s look at it in action:
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT playerid, teamid, g_1b, g_2b, g_cf from appearances WHERE yearid = 2016 limit 10;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now there is a order in which clauses go where in the SQL queries. Generally its SELECT, FROM,
WHERE, GROUP BY, HAVING, ORDER BY, LIMIT. So when playing around with your queries if you don&#39;t stick
to the order Postgres will throw an error. Obviously you don&#39;t know what all of those clauses do, but
just keep in mind for now that &lt;code&gt;WHERE&lt;/code&gt; clauses will go before `LIMIT` clauses. So if you ran
command above this should be your output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; yearid | playerid  | teamid | g_1b | g_2b | g_cf
--------+-----------+--------+------+------+------
   2016 | abadfe01  | BOS    |    0 |    0 |    0
   2016 | abadfe01  | MIN    |    0 |    0 |    0
   2016 | abreujo02 | CHA    |  152 |    0 |    0
   2016 | achteaj01 | LAA    |    0 |    0 |    0
   2016 | ackledu01 | NYA    |   13 |    1 |    0
   2016 | adamecr01 | COL    |    0 |   11 |    0
   2016 | adamsau01 | CLE    |    0 |    0 |    0
   2016 | adamsma01 | SLN    |   86 |    0 |    0
   2016 | adlemti01 | CIN    |    0 |    0 |    0
   2016 | adriaeh01 | SFN    |    0 |    7 |    0
(10 rows)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has returned all the players that had an appearance in the 2016 baseball season.
You can also chain these commands as well using logical switches such as AND or OR like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT playerid, teamid, g_1b, g_2b, g_cf from appearances WHERE yearid = 2016 AND g_1b &amp;gt; 100;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will give us all the rows where the &lt;code&gt;yearid&lt;/code&gt; is 2016 and games played at first base is
over 100 games. There are many more ways to combine these as well to help select the data that you are looking
for but this is the basics. There will be a lot of trial and error at the beginning as you get
used to it so don&#39;t despair and just keep at it.
&lt;h2&gt;Aggregate Functions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok so we&#39;ve learned how to select the appropriate columns and rows that we want from our data, but
how do we look at the overall picture? How do we look at say the total goals scored or assists earned over
a season or even a certain time frame? This is done with our powerful aggregate functions and the
&lt;code&gt;GROUP BY&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see with the data each row is an individual game for an individual player so just using
&lt;code&gt;WHERE&lt;/code&gt;won&#39;t tell you the whole story. So let&#39;s try and see if we can calculate
who had the most hits last season in the MLB.
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT playerid, sum(h) FROM batting WHERE yearid=2017 GROUP BY playerid ORDER BY sum(h) DESC LIMIT 10;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which gives us this output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; playerid  | sum
-----------+-----
 blackch02 | 213
 altuvjo01 | 204
 inciaen01 | 201
 gordode01 | 201
 hosmeer01 | 192
 ozunama01 | 191
 andruel01 | 191
 abreujo02 | 189
 lemahdj01 | 189
 arenano01 | 187
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well that column name isn&#39;t very helpful. However there is a simple way to change that using the &lt;code&gt;AS&lt;/code&gt;
command in your query:
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT playerid, sum(h) AS Hits FROM batting WHERE yearid=2017 GROUP BY playerid ORDER BY sum(h) DESC LIMIT 10;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now your output looks much nicer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; playerid  | hits
-----------+------
 blackch02 |  213
 altuvjo01 |  204
 inciaen01 |  201
 gordode01 |  201
 hosmeer01 |  192
 ozunama01 |  191
 andruel01 |  191
 abreujo02 |  189
 lemahdj01 |  189
 arenano01 |  187
(10 rows)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All &lt;code&gt;AS&lt;/code&gt; does is just create an alias for the column. You can do this with any column you want
along with tables as well. It just creates another name for something that you can refer to later on in the query.
In many newer flavors of SQL you can leave out the `AS` and just put a name next to the column, but I wanted to
show the `AS` incase something breaks if  you do that.
This won&#39;t work with &lt;code&gt;WHERE&lt;/code&gt; statements because the &lt;code&gt;WHERE&lt;/code&gt; clause references the raw data
and your alias is created after the fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple other notes on this query. We have to do the &lt;code&gt;GROUP BY&lt;/code&gt; because this table has a row for each player for each team
they played for in the season. A lot of players do play for the same team all season but a lot don&amp;rsquo;t. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t do
the group by you would miss out on those other team hits for that player. The next is the &lt;code&gt;ORDER BY&lt;/code&gt; this tells
the database how to sort the results in this case by hits descending, i.e. from largest to smallest, with the
&lt;code&gt;DESC&lt;/code&gt; keyword. When you alias the &lt;code&gt;sum(h)&lt;/code&gt; column you can just using &lt;code&gt;ORDER BY hits&lt;/code&gt; next time. &lt;code&gt;ORDER BY&lt;/code&gt; will
sort ascending by default unless you tell it otherwise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There several aggregate functions in SQL with the most common being &lt;code&gt;sum, avg, min, max, count&lt;/code&gt;. Respectively
those add the values, average the values, find the minimum value, the maximum value, and last counts the number of values i.e.
the of rows in a column.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next and most important part of an aggregate function is the &lt;code&gt;GROUP BY&lt;/code&gt; clause. This tells
Postgres how we want to calculate the aggregate functions. If we left out the &lt;code&gt;player&lt;/code&gt; column then
the functions would just sum the total goals and assists of every player after the date we gave it. &lt;code&gt;GROUP BY&lt;/code&gt;
though allows us to tell Postgres that we want to group the sums by each player.
&lt;code&gt;GROUP BY&lt;/code&gt; doesn&#39;t just work
for players we can use it on the &lt;code&gt;teamid&lt;/code&gt; column as well or any other categorical column in your database.
In this one that is just mainly our teams and players, but if you were working with another database with
different categorical columns &lt;code&gt;GROUP BY&lt;/code&gt; would work just as well on those with calculating aggregate
stats. If you have some experinece with pandas or R dataframes &lt;code&gt;GROUP BY&lt;/code&gt; in SQL works basically the same
as &lt;code&gt;.groupby&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;group_by&lt;/code&gt; respectively in those langauges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our next tutorial will cover &lt;code&gt;JOIN&lt;/code&gt; so you can finall tell which players are actually accumulating the stats
you are calculating in you queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.5/static/functions-aggregate.html&#39;&gt;Postgres Aggregate Functions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/9532668/list-rows-after-specific-date&#39;&gt;List Rows after Specific Date in SQL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;https://dba.stackexchange.com/questions/22362/how-do-i-list-all-columns-for-a-specified-table&#39;&gt;List All Columns of Table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Travis CI and Codecov with your Python Project</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/travis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:22:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/travis/</guid>
      <description>by Matthew Barlowe I&amp;rsquo;m going to cover two important concepts when it comes to coding: Continuous Integration and Code Coverage. Continuous Integration is the act of merging everyones code into the main code repository several times a day instead of doing it once a day or every few days.
There are pros and cons to this behavior which is beyond the scope of the article, but I like Continuous Integration (CI) because it fits in with my own coding philosophy.</description>
      <content>&lt;h3 id=&#34;by-matthew-barlowe&#34;&gt;by Matthew Barlowe&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to cover two important concepts when it comes to
coding: Continuous Integration and Code Coverage. Continuous Integration
is the act of merging everyones code into the main code repository several
times a day instead of doing it once a day or every few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are pros and cons to this behavior which is beyond the scope of the
article, but I like Continuous Integration (CI) because it fits in with
my own coding philosophy. I like to commit often usually after every
feature/function I create. This is because if something breaks I
don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to go back through lines and lines of code to
figure out what is actually breaking things.
The second part of CI is each merge automatically runs tests to
make sure the new code doesn&amp;rsquo;t break the old code. Automating tests
is a great behavior because it means never forgetting to
run them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tests brings us to the next part of this article: code coverage.
The idea of code coverage concerns the tests run after each
integration of the code. Code coverage examines all tests
and determines what percentage of the code base the tests
actually test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best is to have your tests cover one hundred
percent of your code but that&amp;rsquo;s not always possible. Sometimes
certain functions take to long and can&amp;rsquo;t always be implemented
in a test as tests are meant to be short as possible. Still though,
shooting for one hundred percent code coverage is always a good goal
strive for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tons of platforms out there to implement CI and measure
code coverage for your projects. The two I will be discussing in
this article is &lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org&#34;&gt;Travis CI&lt;/a&gt; for continuous
integration and &lt;a href=&#34;https://codecov.io&#34;&gt;Codecov&lt;/a&gt; for code coverage.
This article will require you have a Github account and be familiar
with &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; so go grab one if you do not already have one.
If you are unfamiliar with git, make sure to read my other
articles on &lt;a href=&#34;https://barloweanalytics.com/git/gitintro/&#34;&gt;learning to use git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last note is that Pytest will be the python testing suite
I will be using for all the tests. I&amp;rsquo;m sure others will work
with this setup just fine I&amp;rsquo;m just not familiar with the exact
syntax to get them to run. Also if you don&amp;rsquo;t have any tests
written for your code then the rest of this article will be
useless to you as well. So go write some tests for your code
and then come back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;setting-up-travis-ci&#34;&gt;Setting up Travis-CI&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shown below is similar to what you will see when
you visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org&#34;&gt;Travis CI Homepage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/img/travishomepage.png&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;Travis CI Home Page&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hit the big green signup button and it will take you to a page
that will have you enter your Github credentials. Enter those
and then authorize Travis CI to access your Github repos. Click
that big green button as well and then Travis should take you
to a page that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/img/travisdash.png&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;Travis CI Dash&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the slider button next to the repo you want to have Travis
CI monitor and then click on the Settings button next to it and
make sure that &amp;ldquo;Build pushed branches&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Build pushed pull requests&amp;rdquo;
slider buttons are also checked as well. Ok now Travis is ready to
the run project&amp;rsquo;s tests with each push to the Github repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t push anything though because Travis won&amp;rsquo;t know what to do with it
because we haven&amp;rsquo;t written the &lt;code&gt;.travis.yml&lt;/code&gt; file for the repo.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/YAML&#34;&gt;YAML&lt;/a&gt; stands for &amp;ldquo;YAML ain&amp;rsquo;t
markup language&amp;rdquo; and is a common format for configuration files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So create a &lt;code&gt;.travis.yml&lt;/code&gt; file inside the root directory of the repo
on your computer and we&amp;rsquo;ll create a basic one for our Travis CI
build below. You can read more about the options you can have in
the &lt;code&gt;.travis.yml&lt;/code&gt; file &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.travis-ci.com/user/customizing-the-build/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;language: python
python:
    - &amp;quot;3.6&amp;quot;

install:
    pip install -r requirements.txt

script:
    - pytest -s test_unit.py
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of configurations you can put in your &lt;code&gt;.travs.yml&lt;/code&gt; file
but for now this basic one will get your tests up and running. Let&amp;rsquo;s break
it down. &lt;code&gt;language&lt;/code&gt; tells Travis what language you will be running the tests
in. This case is python but it could be anything: c++, java, ruby etc. The
&lt;code&gt;python&lt;/code&gt; tells Travis which version of Python we want to run the tests in. This
one is Python 3.6. If you are using a different version of Python please change
this to reflect that version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your tests require any non standard packages you would tell Travis that
in the &lt;code&gt;intsall&lt;/code&gt; section of the YAML file. A &lt;code&gt;requirements.txt&lt;/code&gt; file holds
all the Python packages the code needs to run and Travis installs them before
it trys to run your tests. Not adding this line will cause automatic failure
of your tests due to &lt;code&gt;ImportErrors&lt;/code&gt; if the code uses non base Python packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next is the &lt;code&gt;script&lt;/code&gt; part of the YAML file. Here Travis looks to see exactly
what tests we want to run each time we push to the repo. Our file is telling
Travis to run the &lt;code&gt;test_unit.py&lt;/code&gt; file and take the output of those tests to
determine whether our build is successful or not. Change &lt;code&gt;test_unit.py&lt;/code&gt; to
whatever the name of your test file is and Travis will run that instead.
Travis will only determine the build is successful if all the tests pass;
if any test fails it will determine that the build is failing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save this file and then push it to your repo on Github. Goto your Build History
on Travis CI and you will see Travis spinning up a virtual machine with the
settings you passed it in the &lt;code&gt;.travis.yml&lt;/code&gt; file. This is after a successful
test for my &lt;code&gt;nba_scraper&lt;/code&gt; package but the look should be similar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/img/travisbuild.png&#34; alt=&#34;Travis build&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all the tests pass the build will turn green and if they fail then
it will turn red. And now you have Continous Integration setup for your
python project! This means that every time you push a commit to your
python project Github repo, Travis will clone the repo and run the tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last thing to mention is that if you&amp;rsquo;d like the build badge on your
Github repo README.md just click on the badge you see on the Travis
build page and select the Markdown option. Take markdown it gives you
and paste it at the top your README.md file commit and push to the Github
repo and you&amp;rsquo;ll have your own shiny build: passing badge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;setting-up-codecov&#34;&gt;Setting up Codecov&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok know that Travis CI is up and running with the repo adding the
Code Coverage reports is just a few more steps. First you need to
&lt;code&gt;pip install pytest-cov codecov&lt;/code&gt; and add the packages to your
&lt;code&gt;requirements.txt&lt;/code&gt; file so Travis will know to install them as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://codecov.io&#34;&gt;Codecov&lt;/a&gt; and link your Github account.
Codecov will then show a page saying no repos are linked to it and
giving you a repository upload token. You won&amp;rsquo;t need that because
Codecov doesn&amp;rsquo;t require the token from &lt;strong&gt;public repositories&lt;/strong&gt; originating
from Travis CI, Circle CI, or AppVeyor CI. If you want to pass
private repositories then you will need to add that to your &lt;code&gt;.travis.yml&lt;/code&gt;
file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that your Codecov account is created, the next step is to edit
the &lt;code&gt;.travis.yml&lt;/code&gt; file to tell Travis to run it after our tests
are done. So open the &lt;code&gt;.travis.yml&lt;/code&gt; file and add these lines to it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;language: python
python:
    - &amp;quot;3.6&amp;quot;

install:
    pip install -r requirements.txt

script:
    - pytest -s --cov=nba_scraper test_unit.py

env:
    - CODECOV_TOKEN=&amp;lt;token&amp;gt;#IF ONLY YOU HAVE A PRIVATE REPOSITORY

after_success:
    - codecov
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;So its basically the same except for a couple differences. First
is the &lt;code&gt;--cov=nba_scraper&lt;/code&gt; flag to pytest. This tells pytest to measure
coverage for my &lt;code&gt;nba_scraper&lt;/code&gt; module. You would change this name to whatever
the name of the folder is holding your python module. The second part
is &lt;code&gt;after_success:&lt;/code&gt;. This section tells Travis what to do after the tests
are passed which in this case is to send the report to Codecov.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s it! Now save the &lt;code&gt;.travis.yml&lt;/code&gt; file and push to Github.
Travis will do it&amp;rsquo;s thing and then send the code coverage report to
Codecov and you should see something like this on your Codecov main
page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/img/codecovdash.png&#34; alt=&#34;Codecov Dashboard&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;nba_scraper&lt;/code&gt; would be replaced with the name of whatever repository
you were pushing to Github. And now the only thing left to do is to
get the badge for your repo&amp;rsquo;s README.md. Click on your repo&amp;rsquo;s name
from the main page and then goto Settings. On the left will be a Badge
section, click on that and copy the markdown option. Repeate the process
of adding it to the repo&amp;rsquo;s README.md just like you did with Travis. Commit
and push and now you have a shiny code coverage badge next to your
build badge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions/concerns or notice any errors please feel
free to email me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:matt@barloweanalytics.com&#34;&gt;matt@barloweanalytics.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/j0nimost/using-codecov-with-travis-ci-pytest-cov-1dfj&#34;&gt;Using Codecov with Travis CI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/devops/continuous-integration/&#34;&gt;Continuous Integration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.codecov.io/docs/frequently-asked-questions&#34;&gt;Codecov FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/195008/what-is-code-coverage-and-how-do-you-measure-it&#34;&gt;What is code coverage and how do you measure it?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_integration&#34;&gt;Wikipedia Continuous Integration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/pytest-cov/&#34;&gt;Pytest-cov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.pytest.org/en/latest/&#34;&gt;Pytest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re Back!</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 21:36:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>The Rebuild Has Begun Due to a lot (well a few) people asking me about my tutorials I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to bring them back. And It gives me a chance to revamp the old website with a little slicker format. So stay tuned as I slowly work to get things back in the shape they were before. As always you can address any concerns, questions, or requests to matt@barloweanaltyics.com.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-rebuild-has-begun&#34;&gt;The Rebuild Has Begun&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to a lot (well a few) people asking me about my tutorials I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to bring them
back. And It gives me a chance to revamp the old website with a little slicker format. So
stay tuned as I slowly work to get things back in the shape they were before. As always you
can address any concerns, questions, or requests to
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:matt@barloweanaltyics.com&#34;&gt;matt@barloweanaltyics.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
