<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Barlowe Analytics</title>
    <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Barlowe Analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2019 Barlowe Analytics</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 01:39:30 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IDEs of March</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/ides-of-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 01:39:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/ides-of-march/</guid>
      <description>IDEs of March There are many articles about learning to code and mention where to learn or how to learn etc. Very few however mention where you are going to write the code once you learn it! Most beginner stuff have you working at that programming language&amp;rsquo;s terminal, which is great for getting the basics but you&amp;rsquo;ll quickly grow past that. So where does one actually write their source code?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want to Learn to Code</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/learning_to_code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 22:52:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/learning_to_code/</guid>
      <description>So You Want to Learn to Code I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting a lot of inquiries recently asking a lot of similar quesitions. Often these questions are broad and hard to answer in an email or a DM, so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to use my free time no longer taken up by watching sports to write a series of blog posts to answer them as best I can.
One of the big ones I keep seeing over and over again is &amp;ldquo;What are the best resources to learn to code?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability and Statistics: Chapter 1</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/degrootchapter1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 15:34:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/degrootchapter1/</guid>
      <description>Ok this is going to be a series of blog posts about detaling my notes and thoughts as I work through DeGroot and Schervish&amp;rsquo;s Probability and Statistics 4th Edition. This may be useful to you it may not be but I generally find I learn things better if I write down what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about them so without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s begin!
The History of Probability So apparently people have been gambling forever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Basics</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/sqlbasics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 22:16:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/sqlbasics/</guid>
      <description>Ok if you&amp;rsquo;ve read the first tutorial on installing Postgres and getting your first database up and running, you&amp;rsquo;re now wondering &amp;ldquo;So how do I access all this data?&amp;rdquo; Well that&amp;rsquo;s where this tutorial comes in as we are going to cover some of the basic commands in SQL to get the data we want. Ok let&amp;rsquo;s get started and dive right in to our data.
SELECT The SELECT command is going to be your workhorse command when working with SQL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Travis CI and Codecov with your Python Project</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/travis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:22:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/travis/</guid>
      <description>by Matthew Barlowe I&amp;rsquo;m going to cover two important concepts when it comes to coding: Continuous Integration and Code Coverage. Continuous Integration is the act of merging everyones code into the main code repository several times a day instead of doing it once a day or every few days.
There are pros and cons to this behavior which is beyond the scope of the article, but I like Continuous Integration (CI) because it fits in with my own coding philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re Back!</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 21:36:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>The Rebuild Has Begun Due to a lot (well a few) people asking me about my tutorials I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to bring them back. And It gives me a chance to revamp the old website with a little slicker format. So stay tuned as I slowly work to get things back in the shape they were before. As always you can address any concerns, questions, or requests to matt@barloweanaltyics.com.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>