<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Barlowe Analytics</title>
    <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Barlowe Analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 23:22:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://barloweanalytics.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/java/helloworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 23:22:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/java/helloworld/</guid>
      <description>Ok Java is a little different than R or Python in that in order to run any code you have to first create a class object. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet written a tutorial on classes and inheritence which form the basis of Object Oriented Programming.
If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to learn Java coming from Python or R this fact will be very disorienting as you can&amp;rsquo;t can&amp;rsquo;t just type some lines and run them at the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/r/helloworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 23:12:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/r/helloworld/</guid>
      <description> by Matthew Barlowe Some simple Hello World code.
print(&amp;quot;Hello World!&amp;quot;) print(&amp;quot;Hello World!&amp;quot;, quote=FALSE) print(paste(&amp;quot;Hello&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;World!&amp;quot;))  produces this output:
&amp;quot;Hello World!&amp;quot; Hello World! &amp;quot;Hello World!&amp;quot;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loops</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/r/loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 20:51:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/r/loops/</guid>
      <description>by Matthew Barlowe This is a tutorial going over the syntax of loops in R. If you want a break down of how loops work and the philosophy please read my Python loop tutorial. Loops should be a last resort in R as they are slow and inefficient. Often you can do what you need to in loops using the apply family of functions or the purrr package.
for loops for (i in 1:10) { print(paste(&amp;quot;Your number is&amp;quot;, i)) } some_numbers &amp;lt;- c(1,3,5,3,0,10,35) for (i in some_numbers) { print(paste(&amp;quot;Your number is&amp;quot;, i)) }  while loops answer &amp;lt;- readline(prompt=&amp;quot;What&#39;s the best part about Matt?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functions</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/python/functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 20:51:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/python/functions/</guid>
      <description>Work in Progress</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loops</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/python/loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 17:53:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/python/loops/</guid>
      <description>by Matthew Barlowe Loops are an important part of programming in any language. So in this tutorial we are going to go over what they do and how to implement them.
In Python there are two typs of loops: the for loop and the while loop. But before we get into the distinction of the two lets talk about why you want to use loops in your programming.
Why loops?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Hello World</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/python/helloworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 20:24:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/python/helloworld/</guid>
      <description>by Matthew Barlowe &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; is a very common first program for just about any programming langauge. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there&amp;rsquo;s some history behind it, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never bothered to look it up. Usually it&amp;rsquo;s just a simple program of very limited lines that prints out the phrase &amp;ldquo;Hello World.&amp;rdquo; The purpose of this tutorial is to get you setup to write that first program.
Getting Started The first thing to do is open your favorite text editor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Python</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/python/pythoninstall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 19:25:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/python/pythoninstall/</guid>
      <description>by Matthew Barlowe Ok so if you&amp;rsquo;ve read the Homebrew Tutorial you are ready to actually start using it to start programming in python. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read that tutorial and you want to follow this one I sugestt going back and reading that one first. First though we need to get your system properly setup to run python safely and avoid problems in the future. The first step to doing that is to install Apple&amp;rsquo;s Xcode utilities, specifically GCC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homebrew Install</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/unix/homebrew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 18:38:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/unix/homebrew/</guid>
      <description>by Matthew Barlowe Homebrew is a very usefual package manager that can be installed on the macOS system. It&amp;rsquo;s what I use to manage by Python installations along with my SQL database as well. It has a nice, easy to learn, syntax and is simple to install from the terminal on an Apple computer. What is a package manager you ask? Well join me in the next section and we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the details behind it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Git and Github</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/git/gitintro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 17:30:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/git/gitintro/</guid>
      <description>by Matthew Barlowe So if you&amp;rsquo;ve started out doing a little coding either for fun or like me to try and do data analysis of the NHL, then you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard people talk a lot about Git and Github. And if you were like me, you&amp;rsquo;ve even tried to learn it, or use it, but just got so frustrated you gave up and figured it wasn&amp;rsquo;t worth the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Work</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 22:46:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/work/</guid>
      <description>Rpubs Here&amp;rsquo;s some of the Data Analysis I&amp;rsquo;ve done in R. I don&amp;rsquo;t use R as much as I used to but I still love doing simple data exploration/graphing in it.
Github A lot of my public work had to be taken down due as it dealt with NHL analytics. I&amp;rsquo;ve branched out into other things such as NBA analysis and fintech in the public sphere these days.
LinkedIn Standard LinkedIn stuff including some of the presentations I&amp;rsquo;ve done in the past on hockey analytics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorials</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 22:24:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/tutorials/</guid>
      <description>This will be a site hosting tutorials for various subjects in Data Science written from the perspective of working in a Mac OS X environment.
Python  Installation  Installing Python
 
  
 Basics  Hello World
Functions
 Loops
  
  R  Basics  Hello World
 Loops
    Java  Basics  Hello World</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/about/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 21:58:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/about/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>I am a SQL Developer and Stats Analyst for the National Hockey League
This site is built using Hugo static site generator. It is hosted on AWS S3 Buckets using AWS Cloudfront to serve SSL certificates and AWS Lambda to clean the urls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re Back!</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 21:36:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>The Rebuild Has Begun Due to a lot (well a few) people asking me about my tutorials I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to bring them back. And It gives me a chance to revamp the old website with a little slicker format. So stay tuned as I slowly work to get things back in the shape they were before. As always you can address any concerns, questions, or requests to barloweanalytics@gmail.com.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>