<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sqls on Barlowe Analytics</title>
    <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/sql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sqls on Barlowe Analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2019 Barlowe Analytics</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 23:46:03 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://barloweanalytics.com/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Joins</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/sql/joins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 23:46:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/sql/joins/</guid>
      <description>Ok now that you have the database up and can now do some basic queries from the [last tutorial]((https://barloweanalytics.com/sql/sqlbasics/) you are probably wondering how do you actually tell which players are achieveing which stats. In the few tables we looked at there are no actual player names, only what&amp;rsquo;s called playerid which looks like a weird combination of a name and a number. Some aren&amp;rsquo;t even full names either way it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really tell you who is doing what in the database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a New Postgres User</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/sql/createuser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 21:33:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/sql/createuser/</guid>
      <description>Ok so if you&#39;ve come to this point you now have your database up and running and you want to allow others to access it. Some people say it&#39;s not the brightest idea, but hey, this data ain&#39;t going to share itself. Obviously letting them use your account is out of the question because as a superuser that will just allow them to wreak havoc any time they want on your meticulously gathered data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postgres Remote Login</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/sql/login/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 22:25:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/sql/login/</guid>
      <description>Remote Postgres Login 
Ok if you&amp;rsquo;ve been following along with the other tutorials you have seen me use the psql command to login into your database that you&amp;rsquo;ve setup on your computer. But that&amp;rsquo;s not all psql is use for, and in fact it has many diverse properties that you can use to pass SQL queries to the database without ever logging into the server itself. But I won&amp;rsquo;t get into that with this tutorial, instead I&amp;rsquo;m going to focus on using psql to login into a remote Postgres server</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Basics</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/sql/sqlbasics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 22:16:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/sql/sqlbasics/</guid>
      <description>Ok if you&amp;rsquo;ve read the first tutorial on installing Postgres and getting your first database up and running, you&amp;rsquo;re now wondering &amp;ldquo;So how do I access all this data?&amp;rdquo; Well that&amp;rsquo;s where this tutorial comes in as we are going to cover some of the basic commands in SQL to get the data we want. Ok let&amp;rsquo;s get started and dive right in to our data.
SELECT The SELECT command is going to be your workhorse command when working with SQL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install</title>
      <link>https://barloweanalytics.com/sql/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 23:38:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barloweanalytics.com/sql/install/</guid>
      <description>by Matthew Barlowe  This tutorial will cover the basics of getting PostgreSQL setup on your computer and running. We won&amp;rsquo;t actually be working with data in this article, but instead the focus is on the nuts and bolts of what PostgreSQL is and and its structure. But before I get into all that let&amp;rsquo;s start at the beginning. As always these tutorials will be focused on working in a Mac OS X environment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>